Guide to the Philip Hermogenes Calderon Correspondence from John Everett Millais and Frederic Leighton
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Frederic Leighton to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, 1889-1896; Series II
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, 1892 January 28; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 2 pages (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    On black bordered mourning stationery, sent from 2 Holland Park Road, Kensington. Writes that he appreciates Calderon setting aside his own viewpoint about the election. Says that another correspondent has sent him a letter telling him what happened. Remarks that he is "touched by the consolation which" he has received.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, 1893 January 2; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 3 pages (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Written on black bordered mourning stationery. Leighton offers Calderon a set of extracts from various treatises on painting, all regarding the use of asphaltum.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, 1893 January 9; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Written on black-bordered mourning stationery, sent from the Athenaeum Club, Pall Mall. Asks Calderon about meeting either in the next week or week after. Closes with "I'm not trying to let you off, you know."
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1894]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 3 pages (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Sent from The Athenaeum in Pall Mall. Writes that he is concerned that Calderon was too ill to come to Dulwich. Discusses a small portrait chosen for "353" and differences between Calderon's and his own point of view. Asks if Calderon has someone in mind for a particular painting for the Exchange--this is likely referring to what would be Leighton's 1894-5 mural for the Royal Exchange, "Phonecians Bartering with Ancient Britons." Leighton states that he is leaving for "Bayreuth" soon, but will be back. Asks if Calderon can "lend [him] a clever youngster..." to help do preliminary work on the mural.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, 1896 January 10; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 4 pages (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Written on black-bordered mourning paper. Leighton offers textual extracts regarding Venetian painting, and Titian in particular.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    A brief note, written in an angry or frustrated tone. Leighton asks Calderon what could be said at the Dulwich Luncheon, and asks him whether he can use his connection to suggest something. Clearly, Leighton is disappointed and upset. It is not clear to what event this letter pertains. It is not dated.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 15 x 20 cm. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Brief note, sent from Athenaeum Club, Pall Mall to say that Leighton thinks that Calderon's idea (presumably proposed in last letter) "seems to be good."
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 2 pages (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Conveys Leighton's request for an autographed copy of a book by Calderon. Leighton suggests an inscription and mentions a library in which all books "bear some one's autograph."
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    A brief letter in a frustrated tone--Leighton thanks Calderon for some kind of previous communication and says he will write to another artist (name illegible). Expresses irritation over some sort of debate about art and writing.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 2 pages (1 folded leaf); 13 x 20 cm. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    A brief message saying that Leighton would like to be home to receive Mrs. Calderon when she calls. Asks if she can visit on a particular afternoon. Says that he and two of his pictures will be away during the week.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Brief note, sent from Athenaeum Club, Pall Mall. Concerning a mutual acquaintance.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    A brief note indicating notes taken at the top of the page. Notes portion reads: "Do get your pictures done. I hear of too many who will fail...We shall have no exhibitions if we don't take care."
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Brief note from 2 Holland Road concerning social engagements.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 2 pages (1 folded leaf); 18 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Expresses thanks to Calderon. Says that he wrote to Alfred Hunt "who accepts, putting off on purpose the prospects." Letter does not reveal many details but seems to concern assembling a group of artists. Leighton remarks that he now has five men. Closes with long acronym or series of initials.
  - Letter to Philip Hermogenes Calderon, [Circa 1890s?]; Leighton of Stretton, Frederic Leighton, Baron, 1830-1896; Autograph letter, signed; written in pen and black ink. 1 page (1 folded leaf); 13 x 20 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Very brief message to Calderon, saying he is always welcome at Leighton's door.